Guide to the Pro-Fac Cooperative records, 1960-2010.
Pro-Fac Cooperative records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pro-Fac Cooperative records, 1960-2010.
8431
Pro-Fac Cooperative.
5.4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, reports, photographs, videos
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, publications, audiotapes, slides, videotapes and photographs, documenting the history of the cooperative.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Pro-Fac was a major fruit and vegetable processing cooperative founded and headquartered in Western New York. It was formed in 1961 and disbanded in 2012.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, publications, audiotapes, slides, videotapes and photographs, documenting the history of the cooperative.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pro-Fac Cooperative.
Subjects:
Agriculture, Cooperative.; Food industry and trade -- New York (State); Agriculture, Cooperative -- United States; Food processing plants.; Food -- Packaging; Canned fruit -- New York (State); Fruit trade -- New York (State); Vegetable trade -- New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.; Audiocassettes.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Reports and Subject Files
  - History of Pro-Fac (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - History of Pro-Fac, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History Curtice Burns Food, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pro-Fac patch and pin, no date (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports - Pro-Fac, 1961-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports - Pro-Fac, 2980-2988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports - Pro-Fac, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports - Pro-Fac, 1995, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports - Curtice Burns, 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports - Curtice-Burns, 1976-1977; 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annual Reports - Curtice-Burns, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual Reports - Cooperative Grange League Federation Exchange, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Directories, 1974, 1989, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Securities Exchange Commission, SEC Filings, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Real Fresh, Inc. - Contracts, Correspondence, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II. Publications
  - "Newspack", 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Newspack", 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Newspack", 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Newspack", 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Newspack", 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Member News", 1961-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1980-1989, "Member News" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Member News", 1990-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Growth", 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "CMF News" (Comstock Michigan Fruit), 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "CMF News", 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "CB Magazine" (Curtice-Burns), 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "CBPF Magazine", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1997-2000, "The Link" (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Link"2001-2003, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The Link", 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Considering Cooperation: A Guide for New Cooperative Development", 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "American Cooperation", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Offering Memorandum - Curtice-Burns Foods, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Annual and Regional Meeting Notices, 1962-2010 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Regional Meetings - Agrilink, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Apples Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1988-2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1988-2006, Cabbage Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cherry Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1990-2009 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pea Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1983-2008 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Snap Bean Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Snap Bean Committee Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, 1995-2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Series III. Photographs, Slides, Videos, Cassette Tapes
  - Photographs - Directors - Pro-Fac and Curtice-Burns (Box 3, Folder 2-8)
  - Photographs - Lecturers (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - Adams, Mort (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - Cumming, Hugh (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - Hutchinson, Robert (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - McDonald, David (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - Various People (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - Headquarters (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Photographs - Field Shots (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Photographs - Alton (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Photographs - Bergen (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Photographs - Bridgeton (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Photographs - Colonial Provision Co. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Photographs - Comstock Foods (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Photographs - Curtice-Burns Foods, Rochester (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
  - Photographs - Farman's (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Photographs - Finger Lakes Packaging (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Photographs - LeRoy Distribution Center (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Photographs -N.J.H.A. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Photographs -Michigan Fruit Canners (Box 3, Folder 31-33)
  - Photographs - Mt. Summit (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs - Nalley's> (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - Photographs - National Brands Beverage Division (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Photographs - National Oats Company (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Photographs -Silver Floss Sauerkraut (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs -Synder's (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Exhibits at Shows (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Variety of Topics (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - Annual Meetings (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
  - Photographs - Annual Meeting, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Negatives (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - Pro-Fac General (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - Photographs - Art Work (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Color Print Transparencies (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Various slides, and contact sheets with negatives (Box 5)
  - Slides, no dates (Box 6)
  - Videotapes - Meetings, Panel Discussions, Presentations, History, 1980s and 1990s; V-6818-6837 (Box 6)
  - Audiocassettes - Annual meetings, Agrilink and Speakers, 1990s-2001; tr 9859-9876 (Box 6)
  - Film - Pro-Fac Curtis-Burns, no date; F-705 (Box 6)
  - U-matic tapes - Curtice Burns Annual Report - long and short versions, 1987 (Box 6)